

Mobile: (202) 271-4027 E-mail: Ly900@aol.com

www.linkedin.com/in/lynguyendc

Github: <a href="https://github.com/Ly900">https://github.com/Ly900</a>
Location: Washington, DC

## **ABOUT**

I am a **persistent** and **curious** problem-solver who strives to gain expertise in any topics I encounter. I use my past skills and abilities as a teacher to share my knowledge and to meet goals with my team. I love to design, style, and to use JavaScript to make my pages stand out.

## **INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE**

### Full-time Web Development Immersive Student,

General Assembly, Washington, DC (10/15 – 1/16)

- Studied full-stack development in a 12-week program.
- Created independent and team projects:

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Teacher,

Bancroft, Washington, DC (2008-2014),

- Demonstrate leadership abilities as Team Lead (2012-2013), and Teacher Lead (2013-2014)
  - Serve as liaison between administration and teachers
  - Lead in team projects
  - Delegate tasks, assign and meet all deadlines
- Train staff on various school initiatives (application model, math problem-solving, whole brain learning, and responsive classroom).
- Generate interview questions and interviewed candidates for teaching positions and the assistant principal position.

School Without Walls at Francis Stevens, Washington, DC (2014-2015)

- Design unit plans, pacing guides, and lessons to meet District of Columbia Public Schools and Common Core State Standards.
- Problem-solve all issues in collaboration with students, parents, other paraprofessionals, and administrators.

## **SKILLS**

#### **TECH LANGUAGES**

HTML
CSS/Bootstrap
JavaScript
SQL
Ruby
JSON

#### LIBRARIES/FRAMEWORKS

JQuery Sinatra Rails Express Angular

# VERSION CONTROL/ DEPLOYMENT

Git Heroku

#### **DATABASES**

PostgreSQL MongoDB

#### **METHODOLOGIES**

ERDs Wireframing Ajax

#### **OTHER LANGUAGES**

Vietnamese Spanish

## **EDUCATION**

University of Maryland at College Park (2004-2008)

- ♣ Bachelor of Science in Elementary Education
- Cumulative GPA of 3.4, Dean's list, Top 15% Praxis II scores
- Licensed to teach English as a Second Language